Real quick before we jump into design techniques,
قبل الانتقال إلى تقنيات التصميم،
it's important to discuss the purpose of visualizations.
من المهم أن نناقش الهدف من المرئيات سريعًا.
Visualizations can be used for two main purposes when analyzing
يمكن استخدام المرئيات لغرضين رئيسيين عند تحليل البيانات
data Exploratory analysis and Explanatory analysis.
تحليلًا استكشافيًا وتحليلًا توضيحيًا.
Exploratory analysis is done behind the scenes.
يحدث التحليل الاستكشافي خلف الكواليس.
This is the type of analysis where you're searching for
هذا هو نوع التحليل الذي تبحثون فيه عن
relationships in the data or hidden insights.
العلاقات الموجودة في البيانات أو الأفكار المخفية.
Once you've collected the data,
بمجرد جمع البيانات،
you can start asking questions about it.
يمكن أن يخطر في بالكم عدة أسئلة حولها.
The way you analyze data to try and answer these questions is known as exploratory.
تُعرف الطريقة التي تمكنكم من تحليل البيانات لمحاولة الإجابة عن هذه الأسئلة باسم الاستكشافية.
Visualizations built for these purposes,
لا يجب أن تكون المرئيات
do not need to be perfect.
المصممة لهذه الأغراض مثالية.
You're simply looking for patterns.
فأنتم تبحثون فقط عن الأنماط.
Explanatory analysis is done after you find an insight.
يحدث التحليل التوضيحي بعد العثور على فكرة.
Visualizations for these purposes need to be surrounded by
يجب أن تتضمن المرئيات المصممة لهذه الأغراض
a story that points the reader to an insight that answers the question.
قصة توحي للقارئ بفكرة تجيب عن السؤال.
Many times these explanatory visuals were found during the exploratory process.
في مرات عديدة تم العثور على المواد البصرية التوضيحية أثناء العملية الاستكشافية.
But rather than share every step and piece of data that led to this
لكن بدلًا من مشاركة كل خطوة وأجزاء البيانات التي تؤدي إلى هذه
visualization,you ask the question and then
المرئيات، يمكنكم طرح سؤالًا
focus on answering the question with a visualization that supports your finding.
ثم التركيز على الإجابة عن هذا السؤال من خلال مرئيات تدعم استنتاجكم.
There are five steps in the data analysis process.
توجد خمس خطوات في عملية تحليل البيانات.
First, you extract your data.
أولًا، تقومون باستخراج البيانات.
You might get the data from a survey,
يمكنكم الحصول على البيانات من الاستطلاع،
a database, the web or some other source.
أو من قاعدة بيانات أو الويب أو من بعض المصادر الأخرى.
Then you can clean the data.
ثم عليكم تنظيف البيانات.
As a part of this process,
وكجزء من هذه العملية،
you might fix missing values,
ربما يتوجب عليكم إيجاد القيم المفقودة،
determine which columns to keep, round values,
أو تحديد الأعمدة التي يتم الاحتفاظ بها، أو تقريب القيم،
or perform some other tricks to get the data in a way that you can analyze it.
أو إجراء بعض الحيل للحصول على البيانات بطريقة تمكنكم من تحليلها.
The next step is exploring your data.
الخطوات التالية هي استكشاف البيانات.
The visuals used for cleaning, exploring,
المرئيات المستخدمة لتنظيف البيانات،
and analyzing your data are part of the exploratory data analysis process.
واستكشافها، وتحليلها جزء من عملية التحليل التوضيحي للبيانات.
The visuals created here and even during
لا تحتاج المرئيات التي يتم إنشاؤها هنا أو حتى
the cleaning phase don't need to be super pretty or super clear in their message.
أثناء مرحلة التنظيف إلى أن تكون فائقة الوضوح في توصيل رسالتها.
They're just for you, the analyst to determine what is going on in the data.
كل ما يهمكم في هذا الأم هو أن يقوم المحلل بتحديد ما يُجرى في البيانات.
Once you explore the data,
بمجرد استكشاف البيانات،
you might determine a particular analysis that was best to answer a particular question.
قد تحددون طريقة تحليل معيّنة تكون أفضل إجابة عن سؤال معيّن.
Maybe you are predicting sales,
ربما تتوقعون نسبة المبيعات،
or fraud, or home prices,
أو عمليات الاحتيال، أو أسعار المنازل،
when you find an insight to share the visuals used
عندما تعثرون على فكرة لمشاركة المرئيات المستخدمة
for sharing this insight or part of the explanatory visuals.
لمشاركة هذه الفكرة أو جزء من المرئيات التوضيحية.
These visuals tell the story of the finding and what it means.
توضح هذه المرئيات قصة الاستنتاج وماذا يعني.
They motivate the actions and move your audience forward.
إنها تحفز على تنفيذ الإجراءات وتحرك جمهوركم إلى الأمام.
The role of this lesson is to build visuals that will be used for explanatory analysis.
الهدف من هذا الدرس هو إنشاء المرئيات التي ستُستخدم في التحليلي التوضيحي.